woolovers.com 2019-09-20

# Privacy Policy | WoolOvers

**How Woolovers Limited uses your information**

## Contents

  1. Purpose of processing
  2. Retention period for holding your personal data
  3. Your information and third parties
  4. Cookies
  5. Disclosure of information
  6. Security measures 
  7. Access to information 
  8. Consent and enquiries 
  9. Your Rights 
  10. Complaints 

Below we set out our privacy policy which will govern the way in which we process any personal information that you provide to us. We will notify you if the way in which we process your information is to change at any time.

We are a company incorporated in England and Wales under registration number 03445676.

We are also registered with the Information Commissioner's Officer with registration number Z1594402. This registration covers the uses of personal information set out below.

You can access our home page and browse our site without disclosing your personal data save information collected by cookies that we use. More information about cookies and your personal data can be found here.

## Contact Details

Our contact details are:

WoolOvers House  
Victoria Gardens  
Burgess Hill  
West Sussex  
RH15 9NB 

Tel: [0345 073 1044](tel:03450731044)

Monday to Friday, 8:30am to 7pm  
Saturday, 9am to 5pm  
Sunday, 10am to 4pm

Email : [privacy@woolovers.com](mailto:privacy@woolovers.com)

## Who may process data

Your personal information (which includes your name, address, email address and any other details you provide to us which concern you as an individual) could be processed by us.

We may pass personal information to third parties for the purpose of fulfilling orders. More information on third parties and your information can be found here.

## Purpose of processing

**_Why is data collected?_**

| 

**_What data?_**  
  
---|---  
  
For the purpose of collecting and processing orders from our website.

| 

First name, last name, postal address, email address, telephone number

**Why?** – In order to process any orders you make via our website, we will need to collect the above data to ensure that appropriate records of your order are collected and you receive email confirmation of your order (which includes details of our returns policy). We will also need your name and address to fulfil delivery of your order. Contact details are needed to enable us to contact you should there be a problem with your order. Without the above information, we would be unable to process your order.  
  
For the purpose of providing you relevant marketing materials (inc. newsletters and any special offers).

| 

First name, last name, postal address, email address, telephone number

**Why?** – It is in our legitimate interests to process your data to send you relevant marketing materials once you have made a purchase through our website, or have signed up for an online account with us.

Please note that when you opt out of receiving marketing materials, we will stop sending you any marketing materials.  
  
For the purpose of sending you our newsletter and any special offers.

| 

First name, last name, postal address, email address, telephone number, date of birth (only day and month collected)

**Why?** – If you have consented to receiving our newsletter, we shall send you regular email and postal communications relating to our products. Special offers will also be circulated to you as and when they are available. You have the option to withdraw your consent for your personal data to be used this way – more information about withdrawing your consent can be found here.  
  
For the purpose of undertaking any customer research (inc. carrying out analysis of our customer data and order history to enable us to send relevant communications and market to similar prospects) / development.

| 

First name, last name, postal address, email address, telephone number, purchasing history

**Why?** – It is within our legitimate interests to collect this data to ensure that we provide the best customer experience we can. We use this data to review our practices and processes as a business.   
  
## Retention period for holding your personal data

Any personal data collected by us is retained for 5 years. You have the right for personal information to be deleted before 5 years. More information on your rights can be found here.

## Your information and third parties

We do use third parties to provide services to us from time to time; therefore, we will need to share data with them that is in our legitimate interests for business administrative needs.

If you are visiting a third party site, we are no longer in control of your personal data. Therefore, you should review their privacy policy for more information regarding how they will use your personal data.

Your data could be sent outside the EEA (e.g. to the USA) for marketing and customer profiling purposes. If any data is transferred outside of the EEA, the relevant companies have provided assurances of appropriate safeguards being in place for the transfer (e.g. relevant companies in the USA are signed up to the Privacy Shield).

A list of the types of third parties that we use and how they process personal information is set out in the table below.

**_Third Party_**

| 

**_What Data_**

| 

**_Why do we share_**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Social media networks

| 

Email, telephone number, first name, last name, postal address

| 

Allowing website visitors to share our content and targeting relevant advertising to customers and similar audiences on social media networks.  
  
Online advertising

| 

Email, telephone number, first name, last name, postal address

| 

Allowing us to target relevant advertising to previous customers and similar audiences.  
  
Email service providers

| 

Title, first name, last name, postal address, email address, telephone number, customer ID number, order history

| 

For sending newsletters, product recommendations, transactional and service messages to customers and prospects via email.  
  
Customer profiling and database analytics

| 

Title, first name, last name, postal address, email address, telephone number, customer ID number, order history, mail preference, email preference

| 

Carrying out analysis of our customer data and order history to enable us to send relevant communications and market to similar prospects.  
  
Feedback

| 

First name, last name, customer ID number, email address, order reference, history of products ordered, date of order

| 

Requesting and collating customer feedback and presenting it on our website.  
  
Ecommerce

| 

Title, first name, last name, postal address, email address, telephone number, customer ID number, order history, mail preference, email preference

| 

Providing a software platform for us to manage our websites and ecommerce order processing.  
  
Courier / Postal Service Providers

| 

Contact name, organisation, postal address, email address, delivery telephone number, customer telephone number, comment for postman

| 

In order to deliver customer orders from our warehouse to the recipient address.  
  
Payment Services Providers

| 

Card number, expiry date, name on card, security (CV2) number

| 

To take payment for orders from credit or debit cards.  
  
Customer Prospect Pools

| 

Title, first name, last name, postal address, email address, telephone number, customer ID number, order history, mail preference, email preference

| 

Carrying out analysis of our customer data and order history to enable us to send relevant communications and market to similar prospects.

The participating retailers are active in the following product categories: clothing, collectables, food & wine, gardening, gadgets & entertainment, health & beauty, household goods, and home interiors. They share information on what their customers buy.  
  
## Cookies

More information about our cookie policy can be found here.

## Disclosure of information

In the unlikely event that a liquidator, administrator or receiver is appointed over us or all or any part of our assets that insolvency practitioner may transfer your information to a third party purchaser of the business provided that purchaser undertakes to use your information for the same purposes as set out in this policy.

Your information will not be disclosed to government or local authorities or other government institutions save as required by law or other binding regulations.

## Security measures

We use reasonable efforts to implement security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from unauthorised access, improper use and disclosure, unauthorised destruction or accidental loss. Woolovers Limited website currently uses high-level Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology. This may vary in the future, if we believe that greater security is available.

## Access to information

You may ask us whether we are storing personal information about you by contacting us and, if you request, we will provide you with a copy of the personal data we hold about you by email. We may charge a fee for doing this, but will tell you before we incur any fee. We may also ask for proof of your identity before providing any information and reserve the right to refuse to provide information requested if identity is not established. We also have the right to refuse your request if it is manifestly unfounded or excessive.

## Consent and enquiries

If at any time you wish us to cease processing your information, or you wish to withdraw your consent to us using your personal information for the purposes provided for above, please use our Preference Centre to amend your choices or, send confirmation of your wish to withdraw your consent to us in writing.

In order to access the information on this website, you must signal acceptance of the terms and disclaimer set out above by clicking on the "I accept" button where prompted. If you do not accept any of these terms, leave this website now.

If you have any enquiry or concern about our privacy policy, or the way in which we are handling personal data please contact WoolOvers Customer Services.

## Your Rights

You have rights in respect of your personal information, and this Section explains a bit more about those rights that are applicable to what we do with your personal information and when you can exercise them. If you would like more information about any of your rights, please contact us on the details set out in this privacy notice.

Requesting more information

We hope that you can understand that it is very difficult to cover all the possible ways in which we collect and use personal information. We have tried to be as clear and as open as we can and will continue to update this privacy notice as our use of personal information develops. However, if you have any questions regarding our use of your personal information, we will be happy to give you peace of mind by answering any questions or providing any additional information that we can. If you do have any specific questions, or need anything explaining, please get in touch using our contact details.

Additional rights

In each instance, we may ask you to make your request in writing to the contact details provided for in this privacy notice and provide verification of your identity.

  1. You have the right to request that we rectify any inaccuracy about you that we may hold, in which case we may ask you to verify the corrected information (for example, we may ask for a recent utility bill for proof of change of address);
  2. You have the right to request that we erase your personal information. Please be aware that we can only with such a request if: 
    * Your personal information is no longer required for the purposes it was collected for (for example, we need your personal information to process a refund);
    * The collection, storage or use of the personal information by us is prevented by law;
    * Your personal information is not required for the purposes of establishing, exercising or defending a legal claim such as in the conduct of legal proceedings.
  3. You have the right to request that we restrict or refrain from processing your personal information: 
    * For the time it takes us to verify the accuracy of your personal information where you have disputed its accuracy;
    * Where the collection, storage or use of the personal information by us is unlawful but you decide not to ask for erasure;
    * Where, we no longer need your personal information but you need them for the purposes of establishing, exercising or defending a legal claim;
    * For the time it takes to determine whether we have an overriding legitimate ground to continue to process your personal information, where you have exercised your right to object to processing.
  4. You have the right to object to data portability in respect of information we have collected from you based on consent or for the reason of entering into a contract. If you exercise this right, we will transfer a copy of the information that you have provided to us at your request.
  5. You have the right to object to our use of your personal information: 
    * Where we are using that information based on our legitimate interests, and where we do not have compelling overriding grounds to continue to use your personal information; or
    * At any time, where we use your personal information to send you the newsletter or any other type of direct marketing, in which case it will no longer be used for that purpose, but may use it for another lawful purpose.

## Complaints

You are important to us, and so is protecting your personal information. We have high standards when it comes to collecting and using personal information. For this reason, we take any complaints we receive from you about our use of your personal information very seriously and request that you bring any issues to our attention.

Where you are communicating with us for the purpose of making a complaint, we will only use your personal information to handle, investigate and respond to the complaint and to check on the level of service we provide. Where the complaint is about a member of our team, we may have to disclose your identity to whoever the complaint is about. You may let us know that you don't want information that identifies you to be disclosed and we will try to respect your request; however, it may not always be possible to handle a complaint on an anonymous basis.

If you are unhappy, you can also contact the Information Commissioner's Office to make a complaint directly.
